[sound effects]
Hi. We're going to do an activity dealing with the motion of objects.
My name is David and I'm going to be your guide.
By the motion of objects I mean the motion of any object
like the motion of an object tossed in the air.
For example, imagine a person catapulted upward by a giant airbag.
Or maybe just this ball.
Of course even when the ball looks like it's not moving at all
the molecules are actually jiggling around with tremendous speed.
In fact, the molecules in the air in this room are whizzing around at like 1000 miles an hour.
That's really amazing if you think about it.
So we're going to start by looking at the motion of something pretty simple: just this tossed ball.
Are you ready? Watch.
Two points!