[sound effects]
Hi my name is Laurie, and I'd like to ask you some questions
about car crashes. We're going to be talking about the forces
that the objects exert on each other when they collide
and how they compare.
The first scenario we're going to look at
We have two carts. Can you see those?
Yea
And so, they are equal mass and equal speed
Alright, so for this situation, how do you think the forces of the
the carts on each other compare? Do you think they're the same
or different?
Yea I would think they'd be equal, yea.
Okay why?
Well if they're of equal size and they're going the same speed,
I would think that they'd be the same.
I would think if they're moving at the same rate,
they'd have equal force and push each other away with
the same equal force. I would imagine.
I would probably say the same since they both bounced off
the same amount from each other.
Okay, so we're going to measure the forces and look at that. Let me show you
how the measurement works. You can see when they tap the force sensor to the right
we get this upwards bump.
And when he taps the force sensor to the left we get a downwards bump.
So we're going to let them collide and we're going to measure the forces during the crash.
So now we're going back to the same two carts but now with the measuring on.
So what do you notice?
Well, it's about the same amount except one's up and one's down.
Right, so those forces are equal?
Yes
Well they seem to be the same.
It looks like the same curve above and below.
They're identical.
This time we're going to look at a video of two cars, and we're going to have a heavy car
which is going to crash into a lighter car that is moving slower.
Okay.
This is two cars, you see the sedan coming in from the left.
And it hits the little car.
So, we'll go back to the same idea about the forces, that
the two cars exert on each other during the crash.
How do you think they'll be related?