So what we're seeing here is, that,
when objects collide, even if they have different masses and velocities,
The forces that they exert on each other during the collision are the same.
Mmkay.
And that's Newton's Third Law
I guess the force is equal but the resultant reaction is
greater from the lighter car.
Exactly, Newton's 3rd law says that the forces are equal and opposite.
So the force on the first car is the same size as the force on the second car.
But think about Newton's Second Law. It says the net force on a car is
the mass of the car times the acceleration of the car.
Putting the two laws together, means that the mass times acceleration of the first car
is just as large as the mass times acceleration of the second car.
If both masses are the same, the accelerations are the same, and both drivers feel the same thing.
But if car number 2 has a smaller mass,
then the acceleration must be bigger to keep the equation balanced.
That's why, the driver of the smaller car is affected more by the collision.
Even though the forces on the cars are the same, his motion changes more.
Take a look at the video of the cars with drivers.
The forces on each car are the same but the lighter car's motion changes more
and the driver lands on his face.
Now newer cars have lots of safety features
So the heaviest car may not be the safest.
But doe's it make sense that the same force can cause different changes in motion?
Yea that makes sense
Yea it does.
It makes total sense. I'm surprised, but it makes total sense.