Well since the one's heavier than the other it would probably have more
force behind it as it was going into the smaller car
So, I would think the heavier object would have more force
and, I think the smaller car would probably be in a worse position.
for in a car accident.
So you'd rather be in the bigger car.
I'd rather be in the bigger car [laughter].
Me too.
Okay, so lets look at this now.
Now, we couldn't put force probes on these two cars,
so what we did is we took our carts and we made one heavy and one light
and we're gonna measure the forces too.
So, here we have the carts now.
So you can see this one has like twice as high of the black bar, so this one's the heavy one.
This one's the light one, and they're gonna hit
Oh wow.
So what did you notice?
It's the same as it is
when they both were the same mass.