Hi, I'm Leah. I'd like you to join Robert , Sidney, and me as we learn
about electrostatics.
If you'd like to try some of the same investigations, you can, but if not, that is
perfectly fine.
We'll be using some simple equipment as we learn about electric charge which will be
mostly everyday stuff...
...such as magic tape, styrofoam plates, clear plastic, balloons, and scraps of cloth
and fur.
Of all those things, the magic tape will be the most important. Ready? Let's go!
Okay. Pretty cool. But why was my hair all over the place?
Uh, I don't know. How about we all go sit down and try to figure it out.
Professor: Oh, hi guys!
Hey Professor, we were just playing with the electrostatics and we're trying
to understand it better.
Professor: What are you thinking?
Well, we know that things need to be rubbed together to get charged, but I'm not
exactly sure how that happens.
Professor: M-hm
Robert: Oh and we know that there's supposed to be two different types of charges, but we
haven't been seeing that.
Like when we charge up this rod and that one, both of them attract the paper, so does that
mean they both have the opposite charge of the paper?
Oh, when I was playing with the tape, see if I take one piece and then I take another
piece, ...
... they repel each other. So, like-charges repel each other. So does that mean that I'm
making force when I do this or do I have the opposite charge?
Well, I have an idea. So, it takes energy to rub these things together and it also takes
energy to pull the tapes apart.
So, maybe we're making charge from energy.
Oh and one other thing. Are there two charges or are there actually three?
Cause we keep talking about positive, negative, and neutral.
Professor: Wow, you guys do have a lot of ideas. Okay that's good!
Um, let's see if we can sort some of this out. Let's start with Leah's tape charging
I think.
And let's see if we can do a more controlled experiment there.
Okay, so I've got some tape. I'm going to take a strip about so long.
You guys can do this too. Join in. And I'm going to fold the end of the first piece of
tape over like that. So you got a square tab at the end.
And then I'm going to take a second piece, same length. But this one, I'm going to take
the corners and fold them over...
..to make a pointy tab on the end. So that way we can tell the two tapes apart.
Then we're going to take the sticky side of the pointy tape and we're going to stick it
down on the smooth side of the square tape.
Just as they were on the roll. So, one piece on top of the other. But we don't have the
roll anymore.
So, this is going to be a bit simpler.
Ah! I got a little difference in the lengths, so I'm just going to tear off some of the
end there and get them the same.
Okay. So now we're ready.
And the question is, "When we pull the tapes apart, what do you think is going to
happen?"
Are the tapes going to get charged? And if so, which one would get charged which way?
And if we then bring the pairs of individual tapes back together, what do you think would
happen between the different individual tapes?