Well, earlier when we were rubbing things together, we had to rub
two different things to get a charge.
But with the tapes, they're both tapes so if we pull them apart, neither of them should get a charge
So then if hold them close together after, they're not going to do anything.
Well, all the pieces that I had earlier, they were charged and they repelled each other...
... So, I think that all of our pieces are going to get charged and then they'll repel
each other.
Well, we don't have the roll this time and we have to apply equal force
on both the pieces of tape.
And there's only one side with sticky stuff on it.
So, maybe they're oppositely charged and some pairs will attract and others will repel.
But the pointy side is the only one that has its sticky part on something.
So, maybe just that one will get charged and so then the pointy tapes will repel but the
square tapes won't be charged, so they won't do anything.