So, it looks like you got a bit of a handle on the tape charging now. So, let's look at
rubbing again more carefully.
You were rubbing the rods and tubes there and trying them out with the paper bits.
Let's try rubbing two things against each other and see what happens.
Okay. So Leah, you're in the middle, you can use some pieces of tape to test the charge.
And Sidney, that's a pair of things for you.
This is a foam plate and an acrylic plate and what you want to do is rub them together...
...and we'll see if they get charged and we'll look for any effects between them, okay?
Robert: I got two plates, okay.
Alright... Mine didn't stick.
Sidney: But mine does
Leah: Robert I think you need to rub it harder.
Professor: Why do you think rubbing harder might make a difference?
Sidney: Well, it be because you need closer contact. Actually it's a lot like the tape
case where basically you just need them to be stuck together closely.
Professor: Okay. How did that work for you?
Oh it's sticking now. And if I pull the plate away, the plastic pulls it back up.
Professor: Okay, so electrical force seems to be a lot stronger than the gravitational
force.
And since they're attracted, it means their oppositely charged, right?
Professor: Well, you can check that with the tapes. Try it.
Okay, so acrylic repels pointy and attracts the square
And the foam repels square and attracts pointy.
Okay, so then likes repel. So, then the acrylic must have the same charge as the pointy
tape.
And then the foam must have the same charge as the square tape.
Okay. So now you know how to test for different kinds of charge and you've got a lot of
different things you've been rubbing.
You can try it out and see what kinds of charge they have!