So how do you like that video footage?
Excellent! Pretty, good, eh? And what did you see with the heights?
They went to the same height! I know. The spinning one went to the same height as the one that was not spinning.
That's not what I expected. At all. I really thought the spinning one wouldn't go as high.
Me, too. But now in hindsight, you know, I think of conservation of momentum,
and I think the bullet had the same amount of momentum upward in both cases... That's right.
So the bullet-block combo must have had the same upward momentum, so
of course they go to the same height. It's like, it's obvious, but I needed to see the experiment
to appreciate it. But you know what's bugging me, is when I saw them go to the same height
one block is spinning. So it seems to me the spinning block has more energy.
You're right, it does have more energy! But it goes to the same height.
Maybe the bullet has a way of imparting more to one of the blocks.
But how?