I've gotta say, that was an excellent shot you made. It was totally awesome. When I looked at the video
I saw that that block went basically straight up. Did you see anything else?
There was a little bit of rotation in it but no too bad so I think we had everything very well aligned.
Yea. How high would you say it went?
Well, from the video it looked to me about two feet.
Two feet straight up. OK. Well, why don't we try something slightly different? Got some ideas?
Yea, I think one thing we can try to do is actually slide this over so that
so instead of going into to the center of mass it's actually going to go to the right-hand side of the center of mass.
OK, I think we've got it lined up now. This bullet would definitely come straight and clip the right-hand side of that block.
So what is that going to do to the block?
I think for sure it's definitely going to impart some rotation.
I wonder if it's going to go straight up like the other block did.
That would be one option but it could also veer off to the left.
Yea, that makes sense, too, because if you hit something on the right side maybe it goes off to the left.
But on the other hand, maybe if you hit something on the right side maybe it could swing and end up... to the right.
So what do you think? What do you guys think?