So I think we can definitely conclude the spinning block had more mechanical energy. That's right, it did.
But how does that make any sense? I mean, total energy should be conserved. It should.
So where did that energy come from?
This is a good question. Or, where did the energy go that meant that this one had less energy?
Maybe, because we moved the block off to one side from the end of the gun that
as the bullet entered the block, it could rotate out of the way.
So maybe the bullet didn't go in quite as far.
And if the bullet doesn't go in as far, there's not as much energy deforming the block... That's right...
so there'd be energy left to rotate the block.
Um hmm, and that would mean that the total energy is still conserved.
Right, it's just a different form of mechanical energy which has been imparted to these two blocks.
Cool! Physics works! Physics works!