[Sound effects]
Today we're going to do a really cool experiment. It involves a block of wood and a rifle.
Catrina, tell us about this setup.
Absolutely. So what we have here is a rifle
that is pointed vertically towards the sky. Now this something you should never try at home.
I am a certified range officer and I make sure we are actually doing everything safely in this experiment.
So what will happen is the bullet will leave the end of the rifle and go straight into a block of wood.
OK, and we're trying to aim the rifle exactly at the center of mass of the block.
That's correct.
And so, will the bullet go through the block?
It will not go through the block. We actually tried this earlier in a horizontal fashion and we saw that
it did get lodged in the block of wood.
OK, so it gets lodged in the block
then I'm guessing the block will fly up into the air.
It will.
So I'm going to get well back. Are you ready to go? I'm ready to go.
OK, let's do it!
OK, range is going hot.
Three! Two! One! [sound of rifle shot]