That was another great shot. Totally awesome. I was watching it in slow motion when it was spinning
and it just looked great. It was so great. And did you see how it went up?
It went straight up. I know. It was a bit surprising
because you know, you'd think it would go to the left, but I guess the bullet had only upward momentum
and no side-to-side momentum so it makes sense the block only went up. It had to go straight up.
The question I want to know the answer to is, how high did that spinning block go in comparison to the original straight-up block.
If we're adding rotational energy to the block now, maybe that means we have to take away some of the potential energy
or some of the potential energy needs to be converted, you know, so maybe instead it wouldn't go quite as high.
It could be, but, I mean, it was the same bullet fired from the same rifle, so part of me wants to say,
it's just going to go the same height as the first one.
But also there's this other effect where, sort of like a golf ball,
it could obtain some lift, so maybe as it spins it actually goes higher.
It could generate  some backspin and push against the air and go up. Yeah. Hmm.
I feel like we have to make a prediction before we check it out. I think that's true.
All right, Why don't you make a prediction.