In our first investigation, we learned that there are two types of electric charge.
For now, we're calling them "pointy charge" and "square charge." We learned that they
really are different...
...since like-charged objects repel each other and unlike-charged objects attract each
other.
In our next set of investigations, we'll explore how things actually become charged and
what it means to call a charge either postive or negative.
Okay, so now I think I understand what happened with my hair earlier.
Just like two tapes that have the same charge, they all repelled each other.
But what I don't understand is when you pull two tapes apart, they become oppositely
charged.
Professor: Good question. You actually know a lot about that, but we just have to apply
your knowledge.
Think about the tapes and the sticky stuff. What are they made of?
You mean like on a really small scale? Like atoms?
Professor: Yeah, on a small scale.
Well, everything's made of atoms. So, atoms and molecules, I guess.
Professor: Okay.
So, where does charge come into this?
Leah: Protons and electrons are in the charged parts of atoms.
Sidney: And molecules are made from atoms.
Professor: Okay, so now what holds the atoms together in the molecule?
Robert: Chemical bonds.
Sidney: Okay, chemical bonds are when atoms kind of share electrons.
Professor: Okay, can you say more about that?
Well, when atoms come together, the electrons from one of the atoms kind of are attracted
more to the space in between the two atoms.
Oh, so then the electrons that are in between the atoms will attract the other part of
the atom that's more postive.
And so it'll kind of hold the whole thing together.
Professor: Very good. So, now what happens when we break the bonds between atoms in the
molecule?