Its a difficult issue. It turns out to understand that, you need to know something about
the quantum mechanics of atomic physics.
That's beyond what we'e going to do this course. But let me just show you an example
of that.
We've got foam plates here and we've been rubbing them with things. I rubbed this foam
plate with fur.
That stick really well. Here's another exactly identical foam plate. I rub it with the
paper towel. Almost nothing happens between them.
So really depends upon the nature of the pairs of materials that you're working with.
With the tapes we've been working with, when we pull them apart, we break some of the
bonds in the sticky stuff that's in between them.
And parts of those molecules tend to have an extra electron and parts of them tend to
have lost an electron.
And so enough of those breaks occur in that way that we get attraction between them.
Opposite charges.
So, if I understand this the right way, it means that the sticky stuff sort of has a
chemical reaction with the smooth side of the tape.
So then when you pull them apart, the tape that was on top that lost some sticky stuff,
it lost some of its charge.
And they're oppositely charged now because one tape has more electrons and the other tape
lost a few electrons.
Professor: Good summary.