Okay, I think I understand. But another question, "How can wee tell which is postive
and which is negative?"
Professor: Okay, is there any electrical situation where you can tell what's positive and
what's negative?
A battery. The top thingy, it's postive.
Professor: How do you know?
It says so right on the battery.
But is that the same type of electricity?
Professor: That's a very good question.
Michael Faraday did a little series of investigations to test that very thing almost 200
years ago.
Tell you what. We'll go high tech, we got a charge sensor set up over at the next table.
Why don't we go and see if we can make use that and find out what's going on.
Okay guys. This is a charge sensor.
It's a sensitive device that allows us to detect electrostatic charge. You can find out
about how it works later on.
But today we'll just use it to tell us what's positive and what's negative.
Okay, to use this thing, first we have to make sure if we zeroed it. I've connected the
red lead from it to the ground lead.
And I'm now going to press the "zero" button. So now it's going to be zeroed. I've also
got a couple batteries over here. The two batteries are stuck together.
And our ground lead is connected to the junction between them.
So now what we're going to do is to disconnect the red lead here and we'll see if we can
use it to determine the sign of the charge.
So, we'll start with this thing running and...
..then zero it agin. Okay, Robert pick up the red lead and bring it near the postive
terminal of that pair of batteries.
Robert: Alright. And look! It goes postive.
Professor: Okay, very good. Now bring it to the negatie terminal. Let me zero it first.
Okay bring it near the negative terminal.
Robert: Oh! It goes negative.
Professor: Okay so now we've got a device that we can use to detect negative and positive
charge.
So let's set it up and see if we can figure out what happens with the pointy and square
tapes.
Okay. I'm going to take and connect the red lead to this can here and we'll...
...actually stop this graph and start it again here in a second. So now, let's see.
You want to clear the data on that, please?
Alright, so we're ready to go. This can is going to act as a sensitive antenna to detect
what happens.
And we've got the sheet of aluminum foil here that'll act like a reference.
Just like the piece of aluminum foil connected in between the two batteries acted as a
reference there.
Got some new pointy and square tapes ready to go?
Okay, we'll start our data.
Zero it again, okay.
Robert: So, when I bring the pointy tape in
Leah: It goes positive.
Robert: And when I take it away.
Sidney: It goes down. Bring it in.
Leah: That's pretty cool.
Robert: Yeah, so I guess the pointy tape must be postive.
Sidney: Okay.
Professor: We'll zero it again
Sidney: Alright, well here comes the square tape.
Leah: That's definitely negative.
Robert: Ooo! What happens when I bring them both in?
Leah: It goes up to back around zero.
Robert: Huh
Robert: Oh, look! If I change the distances, I can make the line go up and down.
Sidney: Okay, bring the tapes together and then bring them in.
Professor: Okay, hold it. I'm going to restart this.
Professor: And... okay we're ready to go.
Robert: Alright. So if bring them both together stuck,...
Leah: Hmm, it's around zero, but not quite.
Professor: That's right. It turns out that in handling tapes, you might add a little
bit of charge or take a little bit of charge away...
...and you actually have to be careful about whether you're scuttering around in your
chair or something, you can get charge.
In fact, if you watch electronic technicians, they often have a wrist band that's
connected to a wire to ground.
That's so they don't any stray charge and maybe zap the chip.
Okay, so now you have something you can find out about charges with.
Robert: Yeah, we can measure the charges of all the stuff we've been using.
Professor: Very good. Well, I've got to go now, so I'll leave you all and drop back in
later and see if you have any questions. Have fun.
Sidney, how about you clear the data and we can start over.
Sidney: Alright, sure.
Robert: Yeah, push it again.
Leah: Alright, I'm charged.
Robert: Alright.
Sidney: Alright, let me zero it. Bring it in.
Robert: Alright, that's negatively charged. How about the foam plate?
Sidney: Let me zero it again. There we go. Looks like...
All: That's really negative
Sidney: Let me zero it one more time
Robert: And what about the fur?
It's a little postive.