We already have Professor Jackson hitting the ball and having it go in a circle.
And the question that we're asking is, "What is going to happen once Professor Jackson
stops hitting the ball?"
So, Where do you think that ball is going to go once he stops hitting it with the baton?
Maybe it continues in its circular path?
Professor: Its just going to keep following this way?
Jessica: Yeah
Professor: Okay so let's draw that in as an option. So that'll be option "A."
Can you think of any other directions it might take?
Maybe it stays curved but deviates from the circle a little bit.
Professor: So perhaps it goes sort of like that.
Jessica: Right.
Professor: Okay, I can see that.
Can you think of anything else?
Maybe it just goes straight and abandons its curved course.
Professor: Okay...
...so it'll just continue in a straight line like that.
Jessica: Right.
Professor: Okay
You know, I could also foresee it maybe going this way instead
Jessica: Okay, yeah.
Professor: Possibly, let's go find out.
Jessica: Okay