So, what I have here was we had a bowling ball that was rolling in a straight line...
...and the question I want you to think about is what does Professor Jackson need to do
with a baton in order to get that bowling ball to move in a circle?
Okay, so this is our circular path and this is the bowling ball.
In what way do you think Professor Jackson needs to hit that bowling ball in order to
make it follow that circular path?
Jessica: Hm, maybe hit it on its side?
Professor: Okay, can you come up and show me what you mean by that?
Jessica: Yeah, sure.
Jessica: So, since its already moving and we want it to keep moving, just maybe hit it in
the direction of motion.
Professor: So, you mean like this. In that direction.
Jessica: Right.
Professor: Well let's label that "A." Can you think of any other ways that you might
want to hit the ball?
Jessica: Maybe at an angle since we do want the path to curve.
Professor: Okay, so sort of in this direction. Like that?
Jessica: Mhm
Professor: That's what you mean? Okay, let's call that "B" then. Any other ideas?
We could always hit it perpendicular to its direction of motion.
Professor: So radially inward?
Jessica: Right, yeah.
Professor: So, this direction. Like that.
Jessica: Mhm
Professor: Okay, well let's find out what happens.'
Jessica: Okay.