So Jessica, in these videos, what we saw was when Professor Jackson hit the ball with
the baton...
...he was able to make the ball move in a circle. Now can you think of any other examples
where there's a force that's being applied to keep something moving in a circle?
Jessica: What about those amusement park rides where the passengers move in a circle?
Professor: You know, another really good example is a ball tied to the end of a string
and you whirl it over your head.
Or how about the moon orbiting the Earth?
But there's no string.
Professor: So, what's pulling on the moon?
Jessica: Gravity!
Or what about the Scottish Hammer Throw?
Professor: Oh, I love that game.
Or you know, they have in the Olympics where the person throws the discus.
Jessica: Or what about the "Death Spiral" in skating?
So in all of these examples, what have you seen?
It seems that there's always a force pulling towards the center.
Exactly. And you know, we call that centripetal force and as soon as that force is no
longer acting on the object, what happens?
It veers off course. The object veers off.
Professor: So, it goes in a straight line?
Jessica: Yeah
Professor: It doesn't follow the circle any more, as if it has no memory.