Oh, hi guys. You still working on electrostatics? How's it going?
It's going alright. We managed to figure a few things out with the tape experiment
yesterday.
How the two materials in contact is what tranfers charge in between them.
Professor: Mhm
Yeah, so the rubbing works not because of the heat, but because of increase in contacts
between the atoms on each surface.
So, in that case, you have one surface transferring charge from it to the other surface.
So, then they would be attracted to each other.
And the repulsion happens when you have two surfaces that either have too many or too few
electrons right next to each other.
Professor: Mhm
Robert: But they have to be close because when they're further apart, the force is weaker.
Professor: Very good. Good summary.
Leah: But there is one thing we're not sure about.
When we were playing around with the tape and the plates, our charged objects were
attracting uncharged things.
So, we don't know what made those things attracted to our objects.
Professor: Mhm. Can you give me a good example?
Sidney: Uh, yeah. When I was a kid, my dad would charge up balloons for birthdays.
He'd rub them on his sweater and then stick them onto walls and refrigerators. Basically
anywhere.
Professor: Mhm
Sidney: And that was cool, but now that I think about it, the balloons were charged.
But he didn't do anything to the refrigerator or the walls.
So I wonder, how, without doing anything to them, were they able to stick?
How did he get those things charged?
Professor: Mhm. Any ideas?
Robert: Well, maybe the balloon has charge  and then when he puts it to the wall, some
of the charge goes from the balloon to the wall
And then balloon attracted to that charge? Seems a bit confusing though.
Leah: But the fridge, it's made out of metal, so it's a conductor, so wouldn't it just
conduct all the extra charge away? It shouldn't attract anything.
Professor: Okay, I think we can figure this out.
We think about a refrigerator, it's basically a conductor, but it's a metal shell around
some thermal insulation.
And so we can make a model of that and we can use that to do a little exploration. Let
me get some stuff here.
I've got some chunks of foam over here and we've got some aluminum foil.
We can wrap the foil around the foam blocks and see if we can use that to make a model
of the door.
Let's see. If you stick the middle of the foil kind of at the top of the foam and we'll
just fold it over like that.
And tuck it in like you're wrapping a package or something and wrap it around so the
foil holds on nicely.
Okay, so this is like a refrigerator case and the door.
So we got that chunk of stuff there and we need some way to see what's happening in terms
of charge.
We can use the tapes, but we got some of this tinsel somewhere around. There we go.
So we're going to put some pieces of tinsel on the top. So the tinsel, while it gets
charged,...
...this is conductive tinsel, that'll conduct charges to the tinsel and the tinsel will
spread apart and repel itself.
Kind of like your hair, if you get it all charged up. Doesn't lie down nicely
Okay so we're going to put all this tinsel around here.
So then what I'm going to do is charge up the balloon and I guess we need to know what
the sign of the charge of the balloon is. Would probably be useful to know.
Why don't you all make some pieces of tape, square and pointy tape. And I will charge the
balloon and we'll see what happens.
Got my balloon charged up. Okay. You got the pointy and square tapes.
Sidney: It seems as if pointy is attracted to the balloon. The square was the negative
and the pointy was positive.
Professor: So, what should pointy do?
Sidney: Pointy should attract and there we go.
Professor: Okay, so what's the sign of the charge of the balloon?
Sidney: The balloon must be negative.
Professor: Okay. So, now we know what the balloon is and so what we're going to do, here's
what I'll to do.
To make sure we're not transferring charge, I'm only going to bring the balloon near the
foil.
Okay? And then we're going to hold the balloon there and separate the second piece, the
cabinet from the door, so to speak.
Okay, and then I'll take the balloon away. And so my question to you is, "What effect
will this have on the charges in the two pieces of the door there?"
Will they be charged? And if so, what charge will they have?