Well, like-charges repel, so the balloon has got a negative charge...
...so it'll repel the negative charge in the closer door, making it positive.
But the closer door is kind of shielding the back door.
And it's further away, so I don't think anything is going to happen to it.
Professor: Okay.
Leah: Well, the balloon is closer to the front side of both doors, so I think that...
...the positive charges in the boards will be attracted to the front of both.
And then both boards will have a negative back.
Professor: Mhm
Sidney: So I think actually that since the balloon is going to pull the postive charges
towards it and repel the negative charges,...
...that the first board will have postive charge and that the second board will have
will have a negative charge.
Professor: Mhm
Leah: Oh come on! That's a trick question. You never touch the balloon to the door, so
they stay neutral.