So I guess the balloon didn't lose any charge to the wall after all.
Okay. So then, that must mean that we didn't really transfer any negative charge at all.
Yeah, that seems likely. Okay. So now let's see what happens when we put them together.
Slide it back in. Watch that tinsel.
Well, the tinsel reached across and it's hanging down now, so...
...I guess that means the charge was lost.
Sidney: Or...
Or that means that the charge just went back to where it was.
Professor: Okay.
So what would happen if we were to actually let the balloon touch the wall?
Professor: Okay, well let's find out. We'll do that, but this time with a little twist.
We're going to actually split the walls just a little bit apart. So then we can try to
use the tinsel to see what's going on.
Okay.
Okay, I'm bringing the balloon in.
Robert: Oh, the tinsel touching it across the gap.
The balloon is stuck to the wall.
Professor: Okay, separate the wall.
Sidney: It seems the tape is telling us again that the back plate is negative.
Okay, I'm going to take the balloon away.
Robert: Alright, and it looks like...
...like the front plate is still positive.
Professor: Okay.
So I guess that since it's positive, the balloon didn't lose any of its charge at all.
Professor: Very good.
Sidney: The negative charge is pushed back to the back plate leaving positive charge in
the front plate.
Professor: Mhm
Leah: But how do you know that's the charge that moves?
Professor: Good question. It turns out we have to refer to the atomic model here.
We can tell from our tapes what sign of charge we got, but we can't tell which charge
moves.
What do you know about atoms that would tell you about which kinds of charges move in
metals?
Atoms have the electrons on the outside, so the electrons can move around like in wires
and such.
That's the key point. We can tell the net charge of things, but we can't tell which way
they move from our tapes alone.
Professor: So what must be going on the attract the balloon?
Sidney: Well.
Leah: The balloon is negative, so the positive charges in the front plate would be
attracting it.
Aren't the negative charges in the back also going to repel it?
I mean, since the wall was neutral to start with, shouldn't there be the same amount of
positive charge on one as negative charge on the other?
So won't you have the same amount of attraction as you do repulsion?
What could be different about the positive charge on the front plate and the negative
charge on the back plate that would make a difference on the effect on the balloon?
Wait, the distance.
Robert: The distance?
Oh! I get it. Because the negative charges here are further away,...
...the repulsive force is less strong than the attractive force.
Bingo.