Now, when I adjusted the lines, I saw that the acceleration was only half as large for the cart with twice the mass.
Another way of saying this is that the acceleration and the mass are inversely proportional to each other.
Or, that the mass times acceleration is constant.
But we also know that the force is constant in these experiments.
Hmm... could it be that the force is equal to the mass times acceleration?
In fact, we can show that if the mass is held constant,
doubling the force leads to twice the acceleration.
If we put this all together, we come up with the statement that
the net force is proportional to mass times acceleration.
Using appropriate units, we can then say that the net force is equal to mass times acceleration,
which is commonly referred to as Newton's Second Law.