So, we've now seen that as long as there is this pushing force on this cart, it speeds up.
It actually gets faster and faster and faster as long as there is a pushing.
This is what's actually known as Newton's Second Law, or at least it's a precursor to Newton's Second Law.
In order for us to really understand Newton's Second Law we'll have to go back to the lab
and do some more careful measurements.
OK, here we are in the lab where we can reproduce the rocket cart experiment in a much more controlled environment.
I have here a long track and a low-friction cart with a fan attached to it.
Unlike the CO2 container which loses gas and therefore exerts a decreasing force,
the fan will exert a constant force on the cart.
Let's see what happens in this constant-force situation.
Are you ready? Three, two, one...