When I did the analysis, I saw that the velocity time graph was a straight line.
In other words, the velocity increased at a steady rate.
The slope of a velocity time graph is what we call the acceleration,
and what we've just seen is that a constant force leads to a constant acceleration.
In reality, there are many forces acting on an object, so a more accurate statement is,
a constant NET force leads to a constant acceleration.
Now what I'd like to do is repeat the previous experiment with one small change.
I'll use the same fan as before so that we have the same force,
but I'd like to add mass to the cart so there's exactly twice as much mass as there was in the previous experiment.
How do you think the acceleration will change when you have the same force acting on a cart with twice the mass?