[sound effects]
We're here at the tennis courts at Dickinson College to do a very exciting experiment.
And what we have is a canister of compressed gas, carbon dioxide, connected to a wheeled vehicle.
When we open the nozzle the carbon dioxide shoots out and that will push the cart in the other direction.
I'd like to ask you a couple of questions.
When I get on the cart and turn on the nozzle, what do you think is going to happen?
I think that you will be propelled forward and possibly start decreasing in speed.
I basically agree with all that. I think it's going to shoot in the opposite direction of the gas and then slow it down.
Well, we're going to try the experiment and actually see what happens.
Are we ready?
Yeah!
What did you observe?
It's kinda the opposite of what we expected. It took a little time to like gain momentum and then it got slowly faster.
So, it was speeding up?
Yes. So if she has not caught you with the rope you would have kept speeding up and going faster.
Really? So that's not what you thought initially. Maybe we are learning some physics.
It wasn't as dramatic as I thought it might be. I didn't move very fast.
So if we tried it again without me on, what do you think would happen?
I think it would be more of an immediate reaction.. Not immediate, but it wouldn't take as long to speed up.
And you think it would speed up the whole time?
I think so until at least most of the pressure is released.
As long as there is a force acting.
OK, so we have another prediction. We'll try it one more time without a passenger and see if the results aren't a little more dramatic.
What did you see?
It went significantly faster.
Was it speeding up the whole time or did it go at a constant speed?
I believe it was speeding up until the rope stopped it.
Sometimes it can be hard to tell if it's actually speeding up, so we might do a little bit of analysis
and actually try and measure to see if it's speeding up.